

Nguyen Dinh Sang

Java Developer

Date of birth: Jan 9, 1999

Gender: Male

Phone: 0345225651

Email: nguyendinhsang9199@gmail.com

Address: Hoc Mon, Ho Chi Minh, Viet Nam

Website: https://github.com/Nguyen-Dinh-Sang

OBJECTIVE

Experienced and hard-working Junior Java Developer with more than 2 years of experience in developing Java. Working as a Java Developer at FPT Software, I have built backend web applications with foundations in Java 8 and Microservices with Spring Boot and PostgreSQL. I have in-depth, hands-on knowledge of ORM, SQL, OOP, and system integration with third parties. I also have skills in dealing with customers, communicating in English, system design, and teamwork. With intense passion and desire to dedicate myself to the work, I am looking for an opportunity to dedicate and use all my skills to make a contribution to the organization and to further develop myself to become an outstanding employee.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, Kotlin

DB Management Systems: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Oracle, MS SQL, MySQL

Frameworks JSP, Spring, Spring Boot, Hibernate, JPA

Others Experience with AWS

CI/CD pipelines, using Docker

WORK EXPERIENCE

Feb 2022 - Present

Java Developer - FPTSoftware

- Java 8, PostgreSQL.
- Using Spring Boot for REST APIs. Provide services in development, support, and maintenance for multiple modules inside Quality Suite ecosystems.
- Golive successfully two large and considered complex and big projects as the main BE Developer.
- Many times received the title Best Performance, always appreciated for the attitude and quality of work.
- Successfully organized sharing sessions about the experience and business, and training for 4 members.

Mar 2021 - Feb 2022

Mobile Developer - SSG Total Solutions

- Java 8, Dart, PostgreSQL, Oracle, Firebase.
- Designed and built mobile apps using Flutter (Dart), and Android. Oracle EBS, Idempiere (Java).
- Golive successfully with two solution projects for two large domestic enterprises. Received many compliments from customers and the company as the main Mobile Developer and Consultant.
- Trained and supported 3 members.

Jan 2018 - Aug 2020

Android Developer - Freelance

- Java 11, Firebase.
- Built Android apps.
- Designed and developed many applications, with ScreenShot receiving the most downloads (more than 100,000).

PROJECTS

RQS

(Feb 2022 - Present)

Customer	Confidential information
Description	Quality Suite ecosystems provide full visibility from engineering to field servicing, a single location with consistent data, to enable tracking & trend analysis to understand root causes and provide actionable insights on decisions to improve products' overall quality.
Team size	258
My position	Java Software Developer
My responsibilities	 Communicate with BA and Team about requirements to understand customers' requirements from there to evaluate and solution, and estimate time. Prepare for the new feature by learning the required document and technologies. Design ERD, Database. Develop Restful API web services. Implement new features and enhance existing features to suit new requirements. Debug and fix bugs. Implement integration with other modules, migrate data and mail service,
Technologies used	 I built backend web applications with foundations in Java 8 and Microservices with Spring Boot and PostgreSQL. Use Git to manage source, Jira to manage tasks, and Jenkins to deploy some necessary AWS functions for the project.

Bank Inventory

(Aug 2021 - Jan2022)

Customer	Confidential information
Description	Application to manage and check the company's assets or customer's collateral about location, condition, users
Team size	13
My position	ERP Technical Consultant
My responsibilities	 - Worked directly with customers, took requirements, and made some documents. - User interface designed, graphically designed. - Built applications and completed functionality using API. - Developed backend using Oracle EBS (Java): developed functions, and exposed REST APIs for mobile.
Technologies used	Flutter, Firebase, Oracle EBS

B2B - Gas and Oil

(Mar 2021 - Aug 2021)

Customer	Confidential information
Description	Management application (employees, goods, forwarding) for industrial and wholesale customers.
Team size	13
My position	ERP Technical Consultant
My responsibilities	 Worked directly with customers, took requirements, and made some documents. User interface designed, graphically designed. Built applications and completed functionality using API. Developed backend using Idempiere (Java): developed functions, and exposed SOAP APIs for mobile.

CERTIFICATIONS		
2022	ISTQB® Certified Tester - Foundation Level	
2022	AWS Cloud Developer of Udacity.	
2018	Certificate of participation in Hutech Informatics Olympiad - Fujinet 2018.	
2017	Certificate of completion of Android application development course at Khoa Pham IT training center.	

Flutter, Firebase, Android (Java), Idempiere

Engineer of Information Technology

Sai Gon University

Graduated 2022

Technologies used

EDUCATION

INTERESTS

Cooking.

Reading books: skills, technology, personal development.

Playing sports: street gymnastics, jogging.

Sep 2017 - Jul 2022